shopnbc.com 2019-08-09

# Evine | Boutique Shopping

**Effective November 8, 2018**

**Scope of this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy describes how Evine Live Inc. (“Evine”) uses, shares and protects the personal information we collect through Evine’s websites (“Websites”), including evine.com ("evine.com") and affiliated websites containing links to this Privacy Policy, Evine’s telephone ordering and interactive voice response services (“Telephone Services”) and Evine’s mobile and other applications (“Applications”) (hereinafter, the Websites, Telephone Services, and Applications are referred to collectively as the “Evine Systems”). This Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the Evine [Terms of Use](https://www.evine.com/p/help/evine/terms-of-use/).

**Your Consent to This Privacy Policy**

By browsing or using the Evine Systems, you are agreeing to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Evine Systems.

**This Privacy Policy May Change**

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version on evine.com. Your use of the Evine Systems following any such change constitutes your agreement that all personal information collected from or about you through the Evine Systems after the revised Privacy Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy.

The date the Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You may access the current version of this Privacy Policy at any time by clicking on the link marked "Privacy" at the bottom of each page on evine.com and other locations in the Evine Systems.

**Questions Concerning Our Online Privacy Practices**

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please email us at customercare@evine.com or write to us at Evine Live Inc., Legal Department, 6740 Shady Oak Road, Eden Prairie, Minnesota 55344.

**Privacy Notices**

This Privacy Policy may be supplemented or amended from time to time by "privacy notices" posted on the Evine Systems. For example, certain pages of Evine’s Websites may contain privacy notices providing details about the ways we use or share the personal information we collect on those pages.

**What Information Does Evine Collect?**

**Information You Give Us**

We collect the personal information you knowingly and voluntarily provide when you use the Evine Systems – for example, the information you provide when you register, create an account, sign-in, search, apply for credit, participate in a contest or questionnaire, submit reviews, sign up for our e-mails, communicate with customer service, or purchase products, services and other retail offerings (“Merchandise”). Depending on how you use the Evine Systems, you may supply us with information such as your name, address, phone number, email address, credit card information, or information about people to whom purchases will be shipped (for example, a gift recipient).

**Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser**

We collect information that is sent to us by your web browser, including but not limited to your IP address or device identifier, the address of the web page you were visiting when you accessed the Evine Websites or Applications, the date and time of your visit, your location, and information about your computer's operating system or mobile device. Please check your browser or mobile device if you want to learn what information your browser or mobile device sends or how to change your settings. We use this information in part to create statistics that help us improve the Evine Websites and Applications and make them more compatible with the technology used by our visitors. If you have created a user identity on one of your visits to the Evine Websites or Applications or if you access the Evine Websites or Applications by clicking on a link in an email we have sent you, we may combine the information provided by your browser with other information that identifies you personally.

**Information We Collect Using Cookies and Other Web Technologies**

We use "cookies" and other web technologies to collect information and support certain features of the Evine Websites or Applications. For example, we use these technologies to collect information about the ways visitors use the Evine Websites or Applications —which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. Cookies and other web technologies are also used to support the features and functionality of the Evine Websites or Applications, for example, to track the contents of your shopping cart as you move from page to page. These technologies also permit us to keep a record of your previous choices and preferences so that we can personalize your shopping experience and save you the inconvenience of reentering information already in our database. Generally, the information we collect using these web technologies does not identify you personally; however, it may be linked to information that does identify you personally, such as the information you provide when you make a purchase or register to use a special feature of the Evine Websites or Applications. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave the Evine Websites or Applications. Although you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit the Evine Websites or Applications, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of the Evine Websites or Applications.

For example, and without limitation, from time to time we may collect your email address via cookies and web beacons (also known as “pixel tags”) on the Evine Websites through the use of third party partners. These partners may combine your email information with other information they have access to, including mailing addresses, so that Evine may serve relevant marketing offers to you via direct mail.

Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that users can set in some web browsers, allowing users to opt out of tracking by websites and online services. At the present time, there are not yet established universal standards for recognizable DNT signals and, therefore, the Evine Websites and Applications do not recognize DNT.

**Information We Collect From Other Sources**

We may supplement the information collected through the Evine Systems with information we collect in other ways. We may also supplement the information collected through the Evine Systems with information from third parties, including data brokers. By supplementing your profile with information from other sources, we are better able to provide Merchandise recommendations and special offers that may be of genuine interest to you. We may also use this additional information to further personalize the Evine Systems and improve your shopping experience.

**Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies by Our Advertising Agents**

Evine uses third-party advertising companies to place online advertisements on our behalf at websites other than evine.com or Evine’s other Websites. These advertising companies may use cookies and web beacons or pixel tags to target and measure the effectiveness of their advertisements. For example, our advertising companies may place web beacons on their clients' websites. When you visit these websites, the web beacon "tags" your computer with a "cookie" that collects and stores information about your visit to their clients’ websites. Our advertising companies use the information they collect about your use of their clients' websites to customize the advertisements you see when you visit their clients' websites, called interest-based advertising. Our advertising companies' use of cookies and web beacons is covered by their privacy policies, not by this Privacy Policy.

You have choices with respect to online advertising and can tell us and/or our partners not to collect and use this information. Note that if you choose to opt out, you may continue to see ads on evine.com and other websites, but they will not be based on how you browse and shop. To opt out of receiving interest-based advertising from third-parties, visit the following websites:

<http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/>  
<http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/>

As noted above, you can also prevent some automatic collection of information by disabling cookies on your web browser. For more information, see “Information We Collect Using Cookies and Other Web Technologies”, above. 

**How is Information Used and Shared?**

**Use of Personal Information Collected through the Evine Systems** We may use the personal information we collect through the Evine Systems for reasons including:

  * to fulfill your order for Evine Merchandise;
  * to provide you with the information or Merchandise you request or purchase;
  * for security, credit or fraud prevention purposes;
  * to register your purchase with the manufacturer or service provider;
  * to provide you with effective customer service;
  * to provide you with a personalized shopping experience;
  * to display personalized advertising when you visit the Evine Websites or Applications or third-party websites;
  * to contact you with commercial and promotional messages, including but not limited to special offers and other information we believe will be of interest to you;
  * to contact you with information and notices related to your use of the Evine Systems or your purchases;
  * to invite you to participate in surveys and provide feedback to us;
  * to better understand your needs and interests;
  * to improve the content, functionality and usability of the Evine Systems;
  * to improve our Merchandise offerings;
  * to improve our marketing and promotional efforts; and 
  * for any other purposes we identify in a specific privacy notice or other communication to you. 

**Our Corporate Affiliates**

We may share your personal information with our subsidiaries and parent and sister corporations (our "corporate affiliates"), who may use this information to contact you with information and offers they believe will be of interest to you. The corporate affiliates' use of your personal information shall be subject to this Privacy Policy.

**Our Service Providers**

We may share your personal information with companies that perform services on our behalf. Our service providers are required by contract to protect the confidentiality of the personal information we share with them and to use it only to provide services on our behalf.

**Evine-Branded Credit Card Information**

If you participate in the Evine-Branded Credit Card program, the personal information we collect in connection with your participation in that program, including the information you provide when you apply for an Evine-Branded Credit Card, is shared with the financial institution or other issuer that partners with us to provide the Evine-Branded Credit Card program (“Issuer”). Issuer’s use of this personal information is governed by Issuer’s own privacy policy and any contracts between you and Issuer.

**Other Business Partners and Selected Vendors.**

We work closely with certain business partners (including but not limited to Issuer, defined above) and carefully selected vendors to provide you with access to their Merchandise and other offerings. We may share personally identifiable information about you with these business partners or selected vendors, and they may use this information to offer you Merchandise that they believe will be of interest to you or to address any questions or concerns that you may have about their Merchandise. For example, if you do not have an Evine-Branded Credit Card, we may share personally identifiable information about you with Issuer (defined above), who may use this information to offer you products and services that it believes will be of interest to you.

**Extended Warranty Providers and Other Vendors**

If you purchase an extended warranty in connection with Merchandise you purchase through Evine, we will share with the company that provides the extended warranty the information it needs to service the extended warranty and offer you renewal and other options.

**Business Transfers**

Information submitted to Evine or the Evine Systems will become part of our normal business records. Your personal information may be transferred to another company (either a corporate affiliate or an unrelated third party) that has acquired substantially all the stock or assets of Evine, one of our corporate affiliates, or one of our operating divisions, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or liquidation. 

**Government and Legal Disclosures**

We may disclose the personal information we collect through the Evine Systems when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law (or a court order or subpoena); to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce the Terms of Use or other agreements that govern your use of the Evine Systems; to protect the rights, property or safety of Evine, our users or others; or to protect your vital interests. If you have purchased Merchandise from us on extended payment terms, it may be necessary for us to file certain information about you with state or local government offices to protect our security interest in that Merchandise or to provide certain information about you to collection agencies in the event of non-payment or a payment dispute.

**What Choices Do You Have?**

Evine respects your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose your personal information. We generally ask you to indicate your choices at the time that you register as a user of evine.com or another location on the Evine Systems where you provide your personal information. When you register as a user of the Evine Systems, you automatically start to receive information, including commercial and promotional messages, periodically via e-mail. You may "opt-out" of receiving our commercial and promotional emails at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in the particular email. You may also manage your subscription and email preferences by clicking on "My Account" on evine.com, Evine’s Applications or by sending us an email. To send us an email, please email us at [customercare@evine.com](mailto:customercare@evine.com).

For more information on your choices concerning online tracking and online advertising, see the “Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies by Our Advertising Agents” above.

**How Can You Update or Correct Your Personal Information?**

You may update your account settings information, including your name, contact information, credit card information, shipping and billing addresses, and subscription and email preferences at any time by clicking on "My Account" at evine.com. Instructions for updating your information are provided under "Account Settings." You can change your account settings at any time and as often as necessary. When you update your account settings, we may keep a copy of the prior version for our records. You are responsible for ensuring that we have up-to-date and active contact information for you on file, including email address and any telephone number.

Minors who post comments or other information to the Evine Websites or Applications so that it is visible to others are able to request that the information be removed by contacting us by email at customercare@evine.com or writing to us at Evine Live Inc., Legal Department, 6740 Shady Oak Road, Eden Prairie, Minnesota 55344. Note that although we can help make sure the information is no longer visible on the Evine Websites or Applications, this does not ensure complete or comprehensive deletion of your information from Evine’s internal systems and/or other websites and services beyond our control.

**Special Notice to California Residents**

We may share some of your information with third-party companies with whom we have contracts to provide Merchandise and/or with companies that use the information for their marketing purposes. California law permits you to request, once per calendar year, information regarding the disclosure of your personal information (specifically, categories of information and the identity of the third parties) during the previous calendar year to any third party for its own direct marketing purposes. To make this request, please contact us as explained above. 

**Security**

Evine has implemented measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration, and disclosure with industry standard measures in place to protect the security of the personal information we collect through the Evine Systems. For example, we use Transport Layer Security (“TLS”) to encrypt your credit card information as it travels over the Internet, and no credit card information is stored in Evine’s infrastructure. It is important that you understand, however, that no website or database is completely secure or "hacker proof." You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse, for example, by protecting your passwords. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to the Evine Systems. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Evine Systems.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Evine’s Websites may contain links to other websites operated by Evine and its corporate affiliates and service partners. They also may contain links to websites that are owned and operated by unrelated third parties. This Privacy Policy applies only to personal information collected through the Evine Systems. It does not apply to personal information collected on any website that does not contain a link to this Privacy Policy, nor to any website operated by any third party. These websites have their own policies regarding privacy. We recommend you review the privacy policy posted on any website you visit before using the website or providing any personal information about yourself.

**Children and Minors**

The Evine Systems are not directed at nor targeted to children under the age of 13. We do not use the Evine Systems to knowingly solicit personal information from or market to children under age 13 absent verifiable parental consent. If you are under 13 years of age, you should not submit any personal information to us. If you become aware of any personally identifiable information we have collected from children under age 13, please contact us as described above under “Questions Concerning Our Online Privacy Practices.”
